MATT CONNOLLY

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Problem solver who writes code – with an interest in accessibility and projects that positively impact the world. Track record of creating successful full-stack web applications. A decade of business experience while working for large corporations and small businesses. With a passion for coaching, I am looking for an engineering team that has mentorship opportunities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at 100Devs | Saint Joseph, MI | January 2022 — Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications

Recent Projects:

Green Earth Electronics Recycling (Website) – Designed and launched a new company website to modernize the design, made the website responsive, and updated the copy to be SEO friendly and better advertise the available services.

Other Projects: Astronomical Society of SW Michigan *NASA APOD Web App*, Nikki's Cocktails *Recipe Web App*

Freelance Web Developer | Saint Joseph, MI | Jan 2022 — Present

Created full-stack web applications and static websites for clients across small and medium-sized businesses. Some clients included: DK's Creations, Kalamazoo Custom T-Shirts, and ThatMoistBoy (Twitch Streamer).

Head of Sales at Green Earth | Saint Joseph, MI | May 2017 — Present

Green Earth is an electronics recycling company with a mission to keep electronics out of landfills. Oversaw customer relations and established a strategy that increased the electronics weight collected from customers by an average of 18% each year. Developed a custom CRM to manage our customer journey and help target new customer activation.

Research Director at WTOL-TV | Toledo, OH | Apr 2010 — May 2017

Used data visualization and research tools to create powerful, persuasive stories to reinforce the advertising power of WTOL and help our sales team close deals. Made complex audience viewing data easy to comprehend by creating viewer profiles to help our news and marketing departments make content decisions.

VOLUNTEERING

Executive Director at Toledo Rowing Club | Toledo, OH | Mar 2016 — Nov 2016

Planned and executed Frogtown Regatta 2016. Profited over \$21,000, grew team entries by 20%, and covered 94% of expenses with sponsorships and vendor fees.

Rowing Coach at Notre Dame Academy | Toledo, OH | Nov 2014 — May 2016

Developed Coxswain Round Table, a program focused on training coxswains using open discussion, critiquing of race recordings, and developing best practices.

CONTACT

mattconnolly.dev

hey@mattconnolly.dev

github.com/matt-conn

linkedin.com/in/ matthewpconnolly

@mattphilipconn

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Tableau

EDUCATION

MIAMI UNIVERSITY

2005 - 2009

B.S. Business Admin